# **Urbano Gutierrez**

urbanogutierrez.com | 636660527 | ugutitej@gmail.com

## Summary

Analytical minded individual, self-taught coder. Started coding at 15 years old making games, nowadays freelancer Python developer and algorithmic stock trader.

I'm willing to find a job related to Python software development, in a medium to big sized company where I can improve my coding for working in a team of developers.

In 5 years, I would like to keep working in coding, hopefully in a blockchain company as a Data analyst or Python developer.

# Experience

[September 2016 - May 2017]

#### Waiter | London

- Worked in a fast-paced and stressful environment.
- Focused on the customer's satisfaction by giving an excellent service and having in mind their preferences.

[August 2017 - October 2017]

#### Junior Python Developer | Freelancer | Spain - Online

- Created a multiplatform (Windows, Android) GUI app using Python Kivy, the app consists in a manager of assets (crypto, banks) with a connection to a backend based in Flask and connections to various exchanges using REST APIs.
- Made some data mining with Python, Requests, Selenium Webdriver and Beautifulsoup4.
- Created trading bots for crypto markets (Bittrex, CoinBase...) using trend following algorithms and risk management
- Created chatbots in Telegram and WhatsApp

[June 2017 - July 2018]

#### Junior Python Developer | FatWhale | Spain - Online

- Integrated some web services between social platforms for our team communications using APIs and Python backends using Flask and MongoDB. Some of them: Asana, Discord, Telegram, Skype, Monday, Slack, Sentry, AWS, Google Cloud, Docker, CircleCI.
- Established CircleCl and Docker Swarm Hub for continuous integration and delivery in our Github projects.
- Created webApps (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python) to research transactions of Ethereum and recovery of lost IOTA funds with proper backends in Flask.
- Built a data mining engine in Python called HAWK and an account management system for it. It collects data from social networks (Twitter, Reddit, Telegram, Slack...) to feed our internal machine learning trading models. Used Python, Redis, MongoDB, AWS, Google Cloud, Docker, Flask, StackDriver.

[August 2018 - Now]

### Junior Python Developer | Freelancer | Spain - Online

- Developed a time management multiplatform app using Python, Kivy, having its backend in Flask and MongoDB, inside Google Cloud.
- Created a webApp using Bootstrap for a task management website, connected with crypto blockchains. Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery.

## Educacion

IES Puerto del Rosario, Bachillerato Tecnológico September 2012 – June 2014

## Skills and knowledge

- Quick learner, keen to learn and improve skills.
- Confident with databases, MongoDB and SQLite, Excel.
- User of design software such as Photoshop, Illustrator, Gimp and Inkscape
- I am learning Machine Learning and Data Analysis on my spare time.
- Team worker, I enjoy learning from others

Languages: Spanish - Native // English - Advanced

Hobbies: Cyber security, Stock Trading, Music (drummer), Networking, Bitcoin